{"first":{
    "question":"what is the starting situation?",
    "background":"background_1",
    "person":"character_1",
    "fore": "null","face":"face_happy",
    "answers":["book return","I quote a book"," I pick up the reservation"],
    "book return":"palautus",
    "I quote a book":"lainaus",
    " I pick up the reservation":"varaus",
    "book returnColor":"green",
    "I quote a bookColor":"green",
    " I pick up the reservationColor":"green"},
"palautus":{
    "question":"what do you do first when you go inside?",
    "background":"background_1",
    "person":"character_1",
    "fore": "null","face":"face_happy",
    "answers":["I'm looking for a return sign and I'll take the loans there.","i ask the librarian for help.","I’m leaving"],
    "I'm looking for a return sign and I'll take the loans there.":"ongelma",
    "i ask the librarian for help.":"palautettu",
    "I’m leaving":"pois",
    "I'm looking for a return sign and I'll take the loans there.Color":"green",
    "i ask the librarian for help.Color":"green",
    "I’m leavingColor":"red"},
"lainaus":{
    "question":"how do you find the book you want?",
    "background":"background_1",
    "person":"character_1",
    "fore": "null","face":"face_happy",
    "answers":[" I leave immediately","I ask the librarian","I searched by region and category","i use a computer to search"],
    " I leave immediately":"pois",
    "I ask the librarian":"kirja",
    "I searched by region and category":"kirja",
    "i use a computer to search":"kirja",
    " I leave immediatelyColor":"red",
    "I ask the librarianColor":"green",
    "I searched by region and categoryColor":"green",
    "i use a computer to searchColor":"green"},
"varaus":{
    "question":"what you do first?",
    "background":"background_1",
    "person":"character_1",
    "fore": "null","face":"face_happy",
    "answers":["i go to ask the librarian for advice","i go to the reservations shelf","I’m leaving"],
    "i go to ask the librarian for advice":"noukittu",
    "i go to the reservations shelf":"nouki",
    "I’m leaving":"pois",
    "i go to ask the librarian for adviceColor":"green",
    "i go to the reservations shelfColor":"green",
    "I’m leavingColor":"red"},
"pois":{
    "question":"you travel home the way you go?",
    "background":"background_1",
    "person":"character_1",
    "fore": "null","face":"face_happy",
    "answers":["walking","by car","by bus","in some other way"],
    "walking":"null",
    "by car":"null",
    "by bus":"null",
    "in some other way":"null",
    "walkingColor":"green",
    "by carColor":"green",
    "by busColor":"green",
    "in some other wayColor":"green"},
"ongelma":{
    "question":"return is self-service. How do you work?",
    "background":"background_1",
    "person":"character_1",
    "fore": "null","face":"face_happy",
    "answers":["stamp the return and put it on the return shelf","I’m leaving","i ask for advice from someone","i look forward to seeing how someone else handles the return"],
    "stamp the return and put it on the return shelf":"palautettu",
    "I’m leaving":"pois",
    "i ask for advice from someone":"palautettu",
    "i look forward to seeing how someone else handles the return":"palautettu",
    "stamp the return and put it on the return shelfColor":"green",
    "I’m leavingColor":"red",
    "i ask for advice from someoneColor":"green",
    "i look forward to seeing how someone else handles the returnColor":"yellow"},
"palautettu":{
    "question":"what do you do then?",
    "background":"background_1",
    "person":"character_1",
    "fore": "null","face":"face_happy",
    "answers":["I'll quote something","I’m leaving","I will stay"],
    "I'll quote something":"lainaus",
    "I’m leaving":"pois",
    "I will stay":"oleskelu",
    "I'll quote somethingColor":"green",
    "I’m leavingColor":"green",
    "I will stayColor":"green"},
"oleskelu":{
    "question":"what do you do after your stay?",
    "background":"background_1",
    "person":"character_1",
    "fore": "null","face":"face_happy",
    "answers":["I shout and leave.","I’m leaving"," I'll quote something"],
    "I shout and leave.":"pois",
    "I’m leaving":"pois",
    " I'll quote something":"lainaus",
    "I shout and leave.Color":"red",
    "I’m leavingColor":"green",
    " I'll quote somethingColor":"green"},
"kirja":{
    "question":"you found a suitable book. How do you quote it?",
    "background":"background_1",
    "person":"character_1",
    "fore": "null","face":"face_happy",
    "answers":[" i use self service","I ask the librarian to help \/ lend it to me","i put the book back and leave"],
    " i use self service":"itse",
    "I ask the librarian to help \/ lend it to me":"apulaina",
    "i put the book back and leave":"pois",
    " i use self serviceColor":"green",
    "I ask the librarian to help \/ lend it to meColor":"green",
    "i put the book back and leaveColor":"yellow"},
"itse":{
    "question":"What do you do with a loan machine first?",
    "background":"background_1",
    "person":"character_1",
    "fore": "null","face":"face_happy",
    "answers":["I give the Library Card to the vending machine and enter the PIN","i look forward to seeing how others work","I ask help"],
    "I give the Library Card to the vending machine and enter the PIN":"tokavaihe",
    "i look forward to seeing how others work":"hoidettu",
    "I ask help":"hoidettu",
    "I give the Library Card to the vending machine and enter the PINColor":"green",
    "i look forward to seeing how others workColor":"yellow",
    "I ask helpColor":"green"},
"apulaina":{
    "question":"the librarian advises to use the vending machine",
    "background":"background_1",
    "person":"character_1",
    "fore": "null","face":"face_happy",
    "answers":["ask for help using the machine.","you tell you that you are unable to use the vending machine and you specify it.","you don’t borrow anything but you leave."],
    "ask for help using the machine.":"hoidettu",
    "you tell you that you are unable to use the vending machine and you specify it.":"hoidettu",
    "you don’t borrow anything but you leave.":"pois",
    "ask for help using the machine.Color":"green",
    "you tell you that you are unable to use the vending machine and you specify it.Color":"green",
    "you don’t borrow anything but you leave.Color":"red"},
"tokavaihe":{
    "question":"have you picked up the numbers how are you going?",
    "background":"background_1",
    "person":"character_1",
    "fore": "null","face":"face_happy",
    "answers":["you borrow books by taking them one by one from the reader. So that the automaton announces everyone is on the quote list.","the machine reports the problem."," I will not borrow anything but will leave."],
    "you borrow books by taking them one by one from the reader. So that the automaton announces everyone is on the quote list.":"kolmas",
    "the machine reports the problem.":"automaatti",
    " I will not borrow anything but will leave.":"pois",
    "you borrow books by taking them one by one from the reader. So that the automaton announces everyone is on the quote list.Color":"green",
    "the machine reports the problem.Color":"green",
    " I will not borrow anything but will leave.Color":"red"},
"automaatti":{
    "question":"the vending machine will report the problem as you proceed.",
    "background":"background_1",
    "person":"character_1",
    "fore": "null","face":"face_happy",
    "answers":["ask for help and borrow the rest","I will not borrow anything but will leave"],
    "ask for help and borrow the rest":"hoidettu",
    "I will not borrow anything but will leave":"pois",
    "ask for help and borrow the restColor":"green",
    "I will not borrow anything but will leaveColor":"red"},
"kolmas":{
    "question":"are there any problems during the quote?",
    "background":"background_1",
    "person":"character_1",
    "fore": "null","face":"face_happy",
    "answers":["Yes","No"],
    "Yes":"automaatti",
    "No":"hoidettu",
    "YesColor":"green",
    "NoColor":"green"},
"hoidettu":{
    "question":"what do you do after that?",
    "background":"background_1",
    "person":"character_1",
    "fore": "null","face":"face_happy",
    "answers":["I’m leaving"," I will repay the loans immediately"],
    "I’m leaving":"pois",
    " I will repay the loans immediately":"palautus",
    "I’m leavingColor":"green",
    " I will repay the loans immediatelyColor":"yellow"},
"noukittu":{
    "question":"what do you do after that?",
    "background":"background_1",
    "person":"character_1",
    "fore": "null","face":"face_happy",
    "answers":["I'm looking for more to borrow","I only quote reservations."],
    "I'm looking for more to borrow":"lainaus",
    "I only quote reservations.":"vain",
    "I'm looking for more to borrowColor":"green",
    "I only quote reservations.Color":"green"},
"vain":{
    "question":"with what do you borrow reservations?",
    "background":"background_1",
    "person":"character_1",
    "fore": "null","face":"face_happy",
    "answers":["i use self service","I ask the librarian to help\/ lend it to me.","i put the book back and leave"],
    "i use self service":"itse",
    "I ask the librarian to help\/ lend it to me.":"apulaina",
    "i put the book back and leave":"pois",
    "i use self serviceColor":"green",
    "I ask the librarian to help\/ lend it to me.Color":"green",
    "i put the book back and leaveColor":"yellow"},
"nouki":{
    "question":"how do you work?",
    "background":"background_1",
    "person":"character_1",
    "fore": "null","face":"face_happy",
    "answers":["I look for a reservation on the shelf and take it.","please help with the search.","I take it all to myself"],
    "I look for a reservation on the shelf and take it.":"noukittu",
    "please help with the search.":"noukittu",
    "I take it all to myself":"null",
    "I look for a reservation on the shelf and take it.Color":"green",
    "please help with the search.Color":"green",
    "I take it all to myselfColor":"red"}
}